{"tossups": [{"question": "A funerary work from this civilization shows two lovers with braided hair, embracing and smiling. The Sarcophagus of the Spouses was created by people in this civilization, as was the Chimera of Arezzo, which was later owned by the Medici family. This civilization, which was wrongly credited with creating the Capitoline Wolf, produced a statue of Apollo found in its city of Veii. For ten points, name this civilization in ancient Italy whose art influenced that of ancient Rome.", "answer": "<b> Etruscan</b>s", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this President who previously served as a World War II general.", "answer": "Dwight D.<b> Eisenhower</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this first pilot to break the sound barrier.", "answer": "Charles Elwood \u201cChuck\u201d<b> Yeager</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "While this leader was traveling in Australia, unknown assailants used a large wood log in an attempt to derail this leader\u2019s train in the Lithgow Plot. Marcus Sargent fired six blank shots at this leader in 1981 during the Trooping the Colour ceremony. In the event of this person\u2019s death, her government will carry out Operation London Bridge. This queen labeled 1992 her \u201cannus horribilis\u201d, in part due to a tell-all book by Princess Diana. For ten points, name this current Queen of England.", "answer": "<b> Elizabeth II</b> (prompt on Elizabeth) Page 1", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Much of this battle took place at the Chalmette Plantation. Alexander Cochrane helped the losing side in this battle, which led to a siege of Fort St. Phillip. Edward Pakenham led the British in this battle against an army aided by the pirate Jean Lafitte. This battle took place two weeks after the Treaty of Ghent was signed. For ten points, name this victory for Andrew Jackson during the War of 1812, a defense of the most populous city in Louisiana.", "answer": "Battle of<b> New Orleans</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Arrow\u2019s Impossibility Theorem explains a problem with this action when it involves more than two possible options. In 1872, Susan B. Anthony was arrested in Rochester for committing this action, which was addressed by the 19th Amendment. For ten points, name this action through which citizens choose candidates on Election Day.", "answer": "<b> voting</b> (accept word forms; accept elaborations, like mandatory<b> voting</b>; prompt on similar equivalents, like \u201c(participating in) elections\u201d before \u201celection\u201d is read)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "An ancient civilization in this modern-day country left the Anitta Text, outlining how the title leader defeated the last king of Zalpuwa. The 1950s Dorak Affair concerned James Mellaart smuggling artifacts from this country after working on the Neolithic city of C\u00b8atalh\u00a8oy\u00a8uk [chat-ul-HOY-ook]. Another discovery in this nation was uncovered by Heinrich Schliemann at Hisarlik six miles from the Dardanelles Strait. For ten points, name this modern-day country where the ancient ruins of Troy are found.", "answer": "<b> Turkey</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Poor wording in this legislation allowed swindlers to interpret a 12 by 14 requirement to be in inches rather than feet. The 1934 Taylor Grazing Act severely curtailed this legislation. This act was supported by the Timer Culture Act, which gave additional benefits in exchange for planting trees. This act allowed settlers to purchase 160 acres of public land for the cost of a filing fee. For ten points, name this 1862 act that promoted westward expansion.", "answer": "<b> Homestead</b> Act Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Timoleon Vassos was born in this country and led an expedition force to assist in an 1897 revolt. That revolt led to this country\u2019s \u201cBlack \u201c97\u201d in which the Thirty Days\u201d War was fought over control of an island whose largest city is Heraklion. The Ottoman Empire gained parts of Thessaly from this country in that war, which was fought seven decades after Alexander Ypsilantis led this country\u2019s independence movement. For ten points, name this country that, after leaving the Ottoman Empire, became a kingdom with capital Athens.", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Greece</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A piece inspired by this war begins with a tone cluster for fifty-two strings and was originally called <em>8 Minutes, 37 Seconds</em> by Krzysztof Penderecki [krish-toff pen-der-etz-kee]. A cantata about an event during this war begins \u201cI cannot remember everything\u201d and ends with the singing of the Shema. Henryk Gorecki\u2019s<em> Symphony of Sorrowful Songs</em> centers on this war and used text from the wall of a Gestapo prison cell. For ten points, name this war memorialized by \u201cA Survivor From Warsaw.\u201d", "answer": "<b> World War II</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This politician developed the American System, a portion of which, the Maysville Road, was vetoed by Andrew Jackson due to a personal grudge. For ten points, name this Kentucky politician called the \u201cGreat Compromiser.\u201d", "answer": "Henry<b> Clay</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A fleet from this country carried out the Raid on the Medway as part of the second of its four wars with England. This country suffered from the first speculative bubble when the price of tulips skyrocketed and then crashed in 1637. William the Silent secured the independence of this country in the Eighty Years\u201d War. In 1672, this country temporarily held off a French invasion by flooding parts of Holland. For ten points, name this country where the Dutch East India Company operated out of Amsterdam.", "answer": "The<b> Netherlands</b> (prompt on Holland before it is read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "During this battle, Colonel Jules Gaucher died during the opening attack on outpost Beatrice. The losing side in this battle launched Operation Castor, a massive paratrooper attack. After failing to assist besieged troops at this battle, artillery commander Charles Piroth killed himself with a hand grenade. Christian de Castries, as well as over 10,000 soldiers, were captured in this battle during a massive assault ordered by Vo Nguyen Giap. For ten points, name this 1954 French defeat in Vietnam.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Dien Bien Phu</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this U.S. Army general, nicknamed \u201cOld Blood and Guts,\u201d who led the Third Army during the invasion of France.", "answer": "George S.<b> Patton</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man rejected America\u2019s alliance with France in his open letter \u201cTo the Inhabitants</b> <b>of America.\u201d While Military Governor of Philadelphia, this man met with (+)</b> <b>Peggy</b> <b>Shippen and was later court-martialed for profiting from his position. This man, with the help of Ethan Allen\u2019s Green Mountain Boys, led the capture of (*) </b> Fort Ticonderoga. John Andr\u00b4e was hanged after his plot with this man was discovered. For ten points, name this American general who defected to the British after failing to handover West Point.", "answer": "Benedict<b> Arnold</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>In this colony, the loss of the exceptionally large Seri cannon led to a prophecy cursing the town of Selangor until its return. The foreign Operation Claret supported this colony\u2019s</b> <b>path to independence, which sparked the (+)</b> <b>Konfrontasi standoff. This modern-day</b> <b>Konfrontasi standoff. This modern-day</b> <b>country was the site of a Chin Peng-led communist (*)</b> <b>country was the site of a Chin Peng-led communist (*)</b> \u201cEmergency\u201d and the location of the majority of the Straits Settlements. For ten points, name this modern-day country that, in 1965, expelled Singapore.", "answer": "<b> Malaysia</b> (accept British<b> Malaya</b>) Page 9", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>In the prelude to this battle, one side tricked the other into thinking its water purification</b> <b>system had broken. This battle coincided with the attack on (+)</b> <b>Dutch Harbor. William</b> <b>Halsey was replaced by Raymond Spruance for this battle after being bedridden with shingles. Station (*) </b> HYPO broke the JN25b code prior to this battle, allowing American forces to follow Yamamoto Isoroku\u2019s fleet. The<em> Akagi</em>,<em> Soryu</em>, and<em> Kaga</em> were sunk during this battle. For ten points, name this decisive 1942 victory over Japan at a namesake atoll.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Midway</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man was replaced by Leo von Caprivi after his ministers were allowed to report to the king. The Kartell, a right-wing parliamentary coalition, led by this man was opposed by the (+) Centre Party and the Social Democrats. This man supported Adalbert Falk\u2019s May Laws, which targeted the (*)</b> Catholic Church as part of his \u201ckulturkampf.\u201d In one speech, this man said that the questions of the day would be answered with \u201ciron and blood.\u201d For ten points, name this Chancellor of Prussia who created Germany.", "answer": "Otto von<b> Bismarck</b> (accept Otto Eduard<b> Leopold</b>) ", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>A man who incorrectly believed he fired the first shot at this battle was famous because he studied the use of marl in tobacco monoculture in</b><em><b> An Essay on Calcareous </b><b>Manures</b></em><b>. Edmund Ruffin, the \u201cfather of soil science,\u201d fought at this battle, which was preceded by a set of instructions sent by Don Carlos Buell. Instead of the U.S.S. (+) </b><em><b>Brooklyn</b></em><b>, the</b><em><b> Star of the West</b></em><b> was sent before this battle, during which Abner (*) </b>Doubleday fired returning cannon shots. Attacks by P.G.T. Beauregard launched, for ten points, what 1861 battle in Charleston Harbor that started the Civil War?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Fort Sumter</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}